# Austin Downey

Bachelors of Science
Full-Stack Software Developer



2082508543



austinjdowney@gmail.com



https://www.linkedin.com/in/austin-downey/



https://github.com/austinjdowney



https://austinjdowney.github.io/My-Portfolio/

# **Education**

Certificate of Software Development CodeWorks, (2021)

## **Bachelors of Science Psychology**

Pacific University (2015)

- Emphasis on neuroscience with clinical disorders
- Minor in Sociology

# **Volunteering**

# ALTERNATIVE SPRING BREAK THRU PACIFIC UNIVERSITY

-Volunteering in San Francisco with various homeless populations and shelters (40 hours volunteering, March 2013)

#### **PACIFIC UNIVERSITY AMBASSADOR**

Fall 2012 - Spring 2014

-Instructed incoming freshmen from the beginning of freshmen orientation thru the whole first year about the best practices at Pacific and where the most ideal resources were according to their needs.

# **Summary**

A full-stack software developer with knowledge in multiple different coding stacks (i.e., Vue.js, Node.js, C#) with an ability to adapt different concepts on the fly, which includes incorporating my psychology background to provide an emphasis on the user experience (UX). Passionate about full-stack development and watching an application come to life from the beginning.

### **Skills and Abilities**

- JavaScript
- · SCRUM (Agile)
- C#

- MVC design
- · RESTful Api's
- .Net

- Node.js
- Auth0
- MySQL

- SASS (CSS)
- MONGODB
- Chart.js

- Vue.js
- Bootstrap
- J QUERY

# **Experience**

# **Full-Stack Software Development Student**

CodeWorks, 03/2021- Present

- Fast-paced learning environment
- Learned multiple frameworks and languages (see Skills)
- Developed multiple Full-Stack applications:
  - Individually: BugLogger and Keepr
  - Partner: KanBanTeam: CarbonNone

#### Server/Togo Specialist

Olive Garden, 5/2015 - 11/2017; 07/2019 - Present

- Cross-trained in multiple roles (i.e., busser, server, caterer/togo, bartender)
- fast-paced environment that prioritizes time-management and customer service
- Consistently receive guest compliments both reported to the manager, restaurant survey reviews, and online/google reviews

#### **Fitness Counselor-Lead**

Axiom Fitness, 08/2017 - 07/2019

- Promoted to Lead Fitness Counselor after a year of employment and displaying a strong work ethic
- Top 4 in sales out of 20+ fitness counselors multiple times in the 2 years
- Strategic sales approach that was repetitive in nature, but created to be adaptable to the individual potential member

#### Case Manager/Community-based Rehabilitation Service (CBRS) worker Kuna Counseling Center, 09/2015- 10/2016

- Helped individual's develop coping mechanisms to help fight/mitigate triggered responses to help be self-sufficient
- Diagnosis ranged from ADHD, Social Anxiety, PTSD, and more
- Case Manager for individual's (i.e., mainly refugees) that needed assistance finding crucial resources, such as the DMV, job searches, medical appointments, and more.

# **Applications**

#### **KEEPR**

- Full-stack application that was developed in a week that is similar to Pinterest.
- Incorporates Vue.js, C#, Bootstrap, SASS, Auth0, J Query, SCRUM, and MySql.
- Application incorporates multiple different style relationships (i.e., one to one, one to many, and many to many).
- User's are able to create their own vaults and keeps, which are used to add to certain individual vaults.
- Keeps are tracked by the number of times viewed and "kept" in individual vaults.
- User's are able to add another user's keeps to their own vault (i.e., vaultKeeps) and is able to delete them once added to vault.
- User's are able to view another user's profile, which contains their own public vaults and keeps, but a user does have the option to make a vault private upon creation, which hides it from other user's.

#### **CARBONNONE**

-Full-stack application within a group of 4 developers completed in just under 2 weeks.

- Incorporates Vue.js, Node.js, SASS, Bootstrap, 3 RESTful Api's, Auth0, J Query, Chart.js and SRUM
- Application is a carbon emissions tracker for your house (i.e., electric and water usage), bike/walk miles to help encourage other modes of carbon free emissions, and car(s) that incorporate varying gas types that will influence your emissions (i.e., unleaded, diesel, hybrid) in relation to miles driven.
- Able to track your own emissions relative to the national average.
- Able to see your daily score and your last 7 daily emissions on your own and other user's profiles.
- Able to see a daily update of carbon emission news and air quality, based on your current location, on the home page.

#### **BUGLOGGER**

-First full-stack individual application incorporating Vue.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, SASS, Auth0, and J QUERY.

- Able to create "bugs"/data and then be pushed to that "bugs" details page to edit (only for the "bug" creator) that "bugs" information.
- All users can create notes related to that specific "bug."
- Included differing rules where one could not delete a "bug" fully, the status would just switch from open/close, but if you created a note on that "bug" you would be able to delete that note.
- Additionally, be able to filter the closed "bugs" off the page and keep only the open "bugs."

#### **KANBAN**

-First full-stack partner developed application incorporating Vue.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, SASS, J Query, Auth0, and SCRUM.

- An application geared towards the private organization of TODO lists, interests, inventory of materials, and more.
- An individual is able to create a "board" where you are able to make an infinite number of lists related to that "board."
- Create cascading tasks based off those lists, and furthermore be able to leave comments or reminders to help complete your lists and tasks.

#### **INSPIRE**

-Application designed within the first 4 weeks of coding with RESTful Api's incorporating 4 different end points and a real time customized clock.

- Background images from UNSPLASH that on refresh would change to a different HD randomized image.
- Randomized inspirational quotes that would also change on refresh, which also had the author hidden unless the pointer was on hover.
- Weather temperature was included in Fahrenheit based off the city, state you were located in.
- Task Manager to add tasks and then be able to track how many tasks were completed, relative to total amount of tasks, but upon completion would also include a strike through.